LIM, JING-XUAN

JHU-JANELIA JOINT GRADUATE STUDENT A*STAR NATIONAL SCIENCE FELLOW

limj2@janelia.hhmi.org Personal webpage Google Scholar // GitHub

Profile

I am a PhD candidate co-supervised by Misha Ahrens and Dwight Bergles, and comentored by James Fitzgerald, at the HHMI Janelia Research Campus, where I study state-modulation of sensorimotor transformations in larval zebrafish. I am interested in how past experiences, such as past locomotor efficacy and sensory/motor histories, can influence brain representations and animal behavior, and the mechanisms that underlie such modulations.

Skills

Functional imaging

Whole-brain in vivo light-sheet and two-photon calcium and voltage imaging of larval virtual reality environment. Craniotomy, stereotaxic viral in vivo calcium fiber photometry spiking data. Compartmental in freely-moving mice.

Neural data

Distributed computation for simulation Rodent surgery and and analysis of biological data. Development, simulation and analysis slices. In vitro patch clamp and zebrafish fictively-behaving in a of multiscale models of biological neuronal networks in NEURON, using labelling and post-hoc recovery NetPyNE. Encoding models for injection, fiber implantation and calcium imaging and multi-electrode modeling of neuronal morphologies. Python, MATLAB, R, HPC.

Electrophysiology

preparation of acute brain field recordings. Biocytin of cell morphologies using Neurolucida. Extracellular multiunit recordings and iontophoresis in head-fixed, non-anesthetized barn owls.

Education

Johns Hopkins University, United States of America PhD Neuroscience

2017-present

Thesis advisors: Misha Ahrens (Janelia) and Dwight Bergles (Hopkins)

Co-mentor: James Fitzgerald (Janelia)

Thesis: Reconfiguration of brain-wide computation by astrocyte-driven internal states

Fellowship: National Science Scholarship (PhD) from A*STAR, Singapore

Rotations: Ernst Niebur, Shreesh Mysore

University College London, United Kingdom

BSc Neuroscience 2012-2015

Classification: First Class Honours Thesis advisor: Beverley Clark

Thesis: Patch-clamp analysis of miniature synaptic currents in layer 5 cortical pyramidal cells of a

Bardet-Biedl Syndrome mouse model

Scholarship: National Science Scholarship (BS) from A*STAR, Singapore

Experience

Dr Misha Ahrens :: Janelia Research Campus, HHMI JHU-Janelia Joint Graduate Student

Jun 2018-present

Reconfiguration of brain-wide computation by astrocyte-driven internal states

Animals frequently switch between behavioral states in response to changes in their environment, in which they execute different sets of spontaneous and sensory-evoked behaviors. Using functional imaging methods, I aim to provide a computational description of how whole-brain information processing is altered by past experience. Harnessing the power of molecular techniques, I will also perform perturbation experiments in order to understand the underlying network and circuit mechanisms that allow neuromodulatory systems to exert widespread control.

Prof Shreesh Mysore :: Johns Hopkins University

Graduate Rotation Student

Jan 2018-May 2018

Inactivation of reciprocal inhibition between Imc neurons in barn owls

Computational circuit models predict that reciprocal inhibition of inhibition between nucleus isthmi pars magnocellularis (Imc) neurons might underlie flexible categorization in stimulus selection. To test that hypothesis, I performed extracellular multiunit recordings from Imc neurons during iontophoresis of bicuculline. Preprint:

Rx https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.03.13.990952v1

Prof Fu Yu :: Singapore Bioimaging Consortium, A*STAR Research Officer Dec 2016-Jun 2017

Role of ventrolateral hypothalamic SST neurons in feeding behaviors

I developed a custom data visualization and acquisition software for fiber photometry and used it to investigate the effects of sleep-wake cycle on the activity of GCaMP-expressing ventrolateral hypothalamic SST neurons, whose activity controls feeding behaviour. This work contributed to a paper: https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abe4323

Prof George Augustine :: Nanyang Technological University Research Officer Jun 2015-Dec 2016

Reconstruction and simulation of the claustral network

Co-supervisor: Prof William Lytton, SUNY Downstate Medical Center

I developed an *in silico* model of the claustrum with simplified integrate-and-fire spiking neurons tuned to intrinsic electrophysiological properties of different cell types and with connectivity based on optogenetic circuit-mapping data. I then performed a multitude of simulations in exploration of the dynamical features of the network. I presented this work at RIKEN Brain Science Institute Summer Program 2016 and Society for Claustrum Research Annual Symposium 2016. Conference proceedings:

https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/20023294.2017.1349859

Awards

Fellowships

A*STAR National Science Scholarship (BS) A*STAR National Science Scholarship (PhD) 2012-2015

2017-2022

Travel Scholarships

A*STAR-RIKEN Brain Science Institute Summer Program Travel Award

2016

Publications

Journal Articles

<u>JX Lim*</u>, Z Wei*, S Narayan, X Mi, W Zheng, DE Bergles, G Yu, M Rubinov, JE Fitzgerald† & MB Ahrens†. Reconfiguration of brain-wide computation by astrocytedriven internal states. *Manuscript in preparation.*

Y Zhang, M Rózsa, Y Liang, D Bushey, Z Wei, J Zheng, D Reep, GJ Broussard, A Tsang, G Tsegaye, S Narayan, CJ Obara, **JX Lim**, R Patel, R Zhang, MB Ahrens, GC Turner, SSH Wang, WL Korff, ER Schreiter, K Svoboda, JP Hasseman, I Kolb & LL Looger (2023). **Fast and sensitive GCaMP calcium indicators for imaging neural populations**. *Nature 615 (7954)*, *884-891*.

X Mi, M Wang, ABY Chen, <u>JX Lim</u>, Y Wang, MB Ahrens, G Yu (2022). **BILCO: An Efficient Algorithm for Joint Alignment of Time Series**. *Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 35 (NeurIPS 2022)*.

https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper_files/paper/2022/hash/eb5d9195b201ec7ba66c8e2 0b396d349-Abstract-Conference.html

Y Zhang, M Rózsa, Y Liang, D Bushey, Z Wei, J Zheng, D Reep, GJ Broussard, A Tsang, G Tsegaye, S Narayan, CJ Obara, **JX Lim**, R Patel, R Zhang, MB Ahrens, GC Turner, SSH Wang, WL Korff, ER Schreiter, K Svoboda, JP Hasseman, I Kolb, LL Looger (2021). **Fast and sensitive GCaMP calcium indicators for imaging neural populations.** *bioRxiv* 2021.11.08.467793

Rx https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.11.08.467793

SC Phua, YL Tan, AMY Kok, E Senol, CJH Chiam, CY Lee, Y Peng, ATJ Lim, H Mohammad, JX Lim, Y Fu (2021). A distinct parabrachial-to-lateral hypothalamus circuit for motivational suppression of feeding by nociception. Science Advances 7 (19), eabe4323. https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abe4323

HM Schryver, <u>JX Lim</u>, SP Mysore (2020). Distinct neural mechanisms construct classical versus extraclassical inhibitory surrounds in an inhibitory nucleus in the midbrain attention network. *bioRxiv* 2020.03.13.990952

Rx https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.03.13.990952

Talks

<u>JX Lim*</u>, Z Wei*, S Narayan, X Mi, W Zheng, DE Bergles, G Yu, M Rubinov, JE Fitzgerald† & MB Ahrens†. Hidden internal states modulate sensorimotor circuits brainwide. 15th Annual Janelia Symposium (Virginia)

<u>JX Lim*</u>, Z Wei*, S Narayan, X Mi, W Zheng, DE Bergles, G Yu, M Rubinov, JE Fitzgerald† & MB Ahrens†. **Behavioral state-dependent visuomotor processing in larval zebrafish**. 2022 Baier Lab Retreat (Lisbon)

Posters

<u>JX Lim*</u>, Z Wei*, S Narayan, X Mi, W Zheng, DE Bergles, G Yu, M Rubinov, JE Fitzgerald† & MB Ahrens†. Experience-dependent modulation of brain-wide visuomotor processing and behavior. *COSYNE 2023 (Montreal)*.

X Mi, <u>JX Lim</u>, ABY Chen, Y Wang, MB Ahrens, G Yu (2022). **AQuA2: Quantify complex fluorescent brain activity with improved accuracy, scalability, versatility, and more functions.** *Glia in Health & Disease 2022.*

<u>JX Lim*</u>, Z Wei*, S Narayan, X Mi, W Zheng, DE Bergles, G Yu, M Rubinov, JE Fitzgerald† & MB Ahrens†. **Experience-dependent visuomotor processing and behavior**. 30th annual Neuroscience Department and Neuroscience Training Program Retreat.

HM Schryver, <u>JX Lim</u> & SP Mysore (2021). Distinct neural mechanisms construct classical versus extraclassical inhibitory surrounds in an inhibitory nucleus in the midbrain attention network. *Cosyne 2021 (Lisbon)*.

HM Schryver, <u>JX Lim</u> & SP Mysore (2019). Construction of classical and competitive surrounds in the owl isthmi pars magnocellularis. *Neuroscience 2019 (Society for Neuroscience, Chicago).*

JX Lim & MB Ahrens (2019). State modulation of sensorimotor processing. 29th annual Neuroscience Department and Neuroscience Training Program Retreat.

https://jingxlim.github.io/jhu19.pdf

JX Lim, A Sheikhattar, Z Wei, MB Ahrens (2018). Neural oscillations in sensorimotor processing. 28th annual Neuroscience Department and Neuroscience Training Program Retreat.
https://jingxlim.github.io/jhu18.pdf

B Colvert, Y Man, S Pisupati, <u>JX Lim</u>, M McHenry & E Kanso (2018). **Evasion** strategies of zebrafish larvae. *Bulletin of the American Physical Society*., Volume 63, Number 13. **Shttp://meetings.aps.org/link/BAPS.2018.DFD.F20.4

WW Lytton, <u>JX Lim</u>, S Dura-Bernal, GJ Augustine (2016). **Computational models of claustrum subnetworks.** *Conference Proceedings: 3rd Annual Society for Claustrum Research Meeting, Claustrum.*

https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/20023294.2017.1349859

JX Lim, S Dura-Bernal, R Orman, C Kayser, GJ Augustine, WW Lytton (2016). Reconstruction and simulation of claustral microcircuitry based on optogenetic mapping. RIKEN Brain Science Institute Summer Program 2016.

https://jingxlim.github.io/riken16.pdf

Resource

Y Zhang, M Rózsa, D Bushey, J Zheng, D Reep, Y Liang, GJ Broussard, A Tsang, G Tsegaye, R Patel, S Narayan, <u>JX Lim</u>, R Zhang, MB Ahrens, GC Turner, SSH Wang, K Svoboda, W Korff, ER Schreiter, JP Hasseman, I Kolb, LL Looger (2020). **jGCaMP8 Fast Genetically Encoded Calcium Indicators**. *figshare*

https://doi.org/10.25378/janelia.13148243.v4

Theses

JX Lim and BA Clark (2015). Patch-clamp analysis of miniature synaptic currents in layer 5 cortical pyramidal cells of a Bardet-Biedl Syndrome mouse model. BSc dissertation, University College London. https://jingxlim.github.io/ucl15.pdf

Coursework

Advanced training RIKEN BSI Summer Program Janelia-MSRI Summer Graduate School on Mathematical Analysis of Behavior Janelia Fundamental Principles of Microscopy for Biologists Janelia FIJI Image Processing and Analysis Workshop Neuromatch Academy		
Accepted but unable to attend MBL Methods in Computational Neuroscience	COVID-19	2020

Teaching	JHU Neuroscience Boot Camp	Instructor	2019
	Mathematical methods for neuroscience and machine learning	TA	2019
	Learning to use Suite2p workshop	TA	2019

References	Misha Ahrens	James Fitzgerald	George Augustine	
	PhD advisor	PhD mentor	Postbaccalaureate advisor	
	+1 571 209 4174	+1 847 491 5702	+65 6778 2012	
	ahrensm@janelia.hhmi.org	james.fitzgerald@northwestern.egeorge.augustine@ntu.edu.sg		